<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:xliff="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto">
    <!-- The terms that users must agree with in order to use the app -->
    <string name="terms_title">Условия использования</string>
    <string name="terms">Используя это приложение вы согласны с утверждением веры и руководством по переводу, а также распространять свою работу по условиям международной лицензии Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0.</string>
    <string name="view_license_agreement">Лицензионное соглашение</string>
    <string name="license_deny">Нет, спасибо</string>
    <string name="license_accept">Я согласен</string>
    <string name="view_statement_of_faith">Утверждение веры</string>
    <string name="view_translation_guidelines">Руководство для перевода</string>
    <!-- This is the license agreement to use the app. It is formatted as HTML. -->
    <string name="license"><![CDATA[<h2>You are free to:</h2>
<p>Share, copy, and redistribute the material in any medium or format; Adapt, remix, transform, and build upon the material for any purpose, even commercially. The licensor cannot revoke these freedoms as long as you follow the license terms.</p>
<h2>Under the following terms:</h2>
<p>
    <b>Attribution</b> - You must give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. You may do so in any reasonable manner, but not in any way that suggests the licensor endorses you or your use;
    <br/><b>ShareAlike</b> - If you remix, transform, or build upon the material, you must distribute your contributions under the same license as the original;
    <br/><b>No additional restrictions</b> -  You may not apply legal terms or technological measures that legally restrict others from doing anything the license permits.
</p>
<h2>Notices:</h2>
<p>You do not have to comply with the license for elements of the material in the public domain or where your use is permitted by an applicable exception or limitation; No warranties are given. The license may not give you all of the permissions necessary for your intended use. For example, other rights such as publicity, privacy, or moral rights may limit how you use the material.</p>]]></string>
    <!-- This is the translation guidelines that users must agree to before using the app. It is formatted as HTML. Translation on this will wait until we can find a reliable source -->
    <!-- This is the statement of faith that users must agree to before using the app. It is formatted as HTML. Translation on this will wait until we have a reliable source -->
</resources>
