<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:xliff="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto">
    <!-- The terms that users must agree with in order to use the app -->
    <string name="terms_title">Условия использования</string>
    <string name="terms">Используя это приложение вы согласны с утверждением веры и руководством по переводу, а также распространять свою работу по условиям международной лицензии Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0.</string>
    <string name="view_license_agreement">Лицензионное соглашение</string>
    <string name="license_deny">Нет, спасибо</string>
    <string name="license_accept">Я согласен</string>
    <string name="view_statement_of_faith">Утверждение веры</string>
    <string name="view_translation_guidelines">Руководство для перевода</string>
    <!-- This is the license agreement to use the app. It is formatted as HTML. -->
    <string name="license"><![CDATA[<h2>You are free to:</h2>
<p>Share, copy, and redistribute the material in any medium or format; Adapt, remix, transform, and build upon the material for any purpose, even commercially. The licensor cannot revoke these freedoms as long as you follow the license terms.</p>
<h2>Under the following terms:</h2>
<p>
    <b>Attribution</b> - You must give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. You may do so in any reasonable manner, but not in any way that suggests the licensor endorses you or your use;
    <br/><b>ShareAlike</b> - If you remix, transform, or build upon the material, you must distribute your contributions under the same license as the original;
    <br/><b>No additional restrictions</b> -  You may not apply legal terms or technological measures that legally restrict others from doing anything the license permits.
</p>
<h2>Notices:</h2>
<p>You do not have to comply with the license for elements of the material in the public domain or where your use is permitted by an applicable exception or limitation; No warranties are given. The license may not give you all of the permissions necessary for your intended use. For example, other rights such as publicity, privacy, or moral rights may limit how you use the material.</p>]]></string>
    <!-- This is the translation guidelines that users must agree to before using the app. It is formatted as HTML. Translation on this will wait until we can find a reliable source -->
    <string name="translation_guidlines"><![CDATA[<h1>Translation Guidelines</h1>
<p><em>The following statement on the principles and procedures used in translation is subscribed to by all member organizations of and contributors to the <xliff:g id="organization_name">Wycliffe Associates</xliff:g> project. All translation activities are carried out according to these common guidelines.</em></p>
<p>
  <strong>Accurate</strong> - Translate accurately, without detracting from, changing, or adding to the meaning of the original text. Translated content should faithfully communicate as precisely as possible the meaning of the original text as it would have been understood by the original audience.
  <br/><br/><strong>Clear</strong> - Use whatever language structures are necessary to achieve the highest level of comprehension. This includes rearranging the form of a text and using as many or as few terms as necessary to communicate the original meaning as accurately as possible.
  <br/><br/><strong>Faithful</strong> - Use key terms that are faithful to the vocabulary of the original biblical languages. Terms addressing the relationship between God the Father and God the Son should be retained in translated content and clarified, as needed, in footnotes or other supplemental resources.
  <br/><br/><strong>Authoritative</strong> - Use the original language biblical texts as the highest authority for translation of biblical content. Reliable biblical content in other languages may be used for clarification and as intermediary source texts.
  <br/><br/><strong>Pure</strong> - Avoid any political, denominational, ideological, social, cultural, or theological bias in your translation.
  <br/><br/><strong>Expressive</strong> - Communicate the feelings and attitudes of the original text. As much as possible, maintain the literary forms in the original text, including narrative, poetry, exhortation, and prophecy, representing them with corresponding forms that communicate in a similar way in your language.
  <br/><br/><strong>Historical</strong> - Communicate historical events and facts accurately, providing additional information as needed in order to accurately communicate the intended message to people who do not share the same context and culture as the original recipients of the original content.
  <br/><br/><strong>Natural</strong> - Use language forms that are effective and that reflect the way your language is used in corresponding contexts.
  <br/><br/><strong>Collaborative</strong> - Where possible, work together with other believers who speak your language to translate, check, and distribute the translated content, ensuring that it is of the highest quality and available to as many people as possible.
  <br/><br/><strong>Ongoing</strong> - Encourage the periodic review of translations to ascertain when revision or a new translation is needed.
</p>
<h1>Managing and Identifying Translation Quality</h1>
<p>The quality of a translation generally refers to the fidelity of the translation to the meaning of the original, and the degree to which the translation is understandable and effective for the speakers of the receptor language. The strategy we suggest involves checking the forms and communicative quality of the translation with the language community, and checking the fidelity of the translation with the Church in that people group.</p>
<p>The specific steps involved may vary significantly, depending on the language and context of the translation project. Generally, we consider a good translation to be one that is:</p>
<p>
  <strong>Accurate</strong> - Faithful to the intended meaning of the original, as determined by the Church in that people group and in alignment with the Church global and historical, and consequently:
  <br/><br/><strong>Affirmed by the Church</strong> - Endorsed and used by the Church.
</p>
<p>In addition, a good translation is reviewed by the speakers of the language community and is found to be:</p>
<p>
  <strong>Natural</strong> - Using current forms of the language, and
  <br/><br/><strong>Clear</strong> - Strives for the highest level of comprehension by hearers.
</p>]]></string>
    <!-- This is the statement of faith that users must agree to before using the app. It is formatted as HTML. Translation on this will wait until we have a reliable source -->
    <string name="statement_of_faith"><![CDATA[<h1>Statement of Faith</h1>
<p>
  The divine inspiration and consequent authority of the whole canonical Scriptures.
  <br/><br/>The doctrine of the Trinity—God is one, existing in three persons, the Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit.
  <br/><br/>The fall of man, his consequent moral depravity, and his need for regeneration.
  <br/><br/>The atonement through the substitutionary death of Christ.
  <br/><br/>The doctrine of justification by faith.
  <br/><br/>The resurrection of the body, in the case of the just and the unjust.
  <br/><br/>The eternal life of the saved and the eternal punishment of the lost.
</p>]]></string>
</resources>
