<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:xliff="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto">
    <!-- The terms that users must agree with in order to use the app -->
    <string name="terms_title">លក្ខខណ្ឌប្រើប្រាស់</string>
    <string name="terms">តាមរយៈការប្រើកម្មវិធីនេះ អ្នកយល់ស្របនឹងសេចក្តីថ្លែងការណ៍នៃជំនឿ និងសេចក្តីណែនាំអំពីការបកប្រែ ព្រមទាំងយល់ព្រមប្រគល់ការងាររបស់អ្នកក្រោមលក្ខខណ្ឌនៃ អាជ្ញាបណ្ណអន្តរជាតិ Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0។</string>
    <string name="view_license_agreement">កិច្ចព្រមព្រៀងអាជ្ញាបណ្ណ</string>
    <string name="license_deny">ទេ អរគុណ</string>
    <string name="license_accept">ខ្ញុំយល់ព្រមទទួលយក</string>
    <string name="view_statement_of_faith">សេចក្តីថ្លែងការណ៍នៃជំនឿ</string>
    <string name="view_translation_guidelines">គោលការណែនាំអំពីការបកប្រែ​</string>
    <!-- This is the license agreement to use the app. It is formatted as HTML. -->
    <string name="license"><![CDATA[<h2>អ្នកមានសិទ្ធិ:</h2>
<p>ចែករំលែក, ចម្លង, និងចែកចាយឯកសារតាមប្រព័ន្ធឃោសនាផ្សព្វផ្សាយសាធារណៈ ឬទម្រង់ណាមួយដែលមានជាអាទិ៍ៈ យកលំនាំតាម, កាត់តចងក្រង, ផ្លាស់ប្ដូរទ្រង់ទ្រាយ, និងបន្ថែមខ្លឹមសារលើឯកសារនេះសម្រាប់គោលបំណងណាមួយ សូម្បីតែសម្រាប់គោលបំណងពាណិជ្ជកម្មក៏បាន។ អ្នកផ្តល់អាជ្ញាបណ្ណមិនអាចដកហូតសិទ្ធិសេរីភាពទាំងនេះបានឡើយ ដរាបណាអ្នកអនុវត្តតាមលក្ខខណ្ឌនៃអាជ្ញាបណ្ណនេះ។</p>
<h2>ក្រោមលក្ខខណ្ឌដូចតទៅ:</h2>
<p>
    <b>ការរក្សាកម្មសិទ្ធិ</b> - អ្នកត្រូវតែផ្តល់កិត្តិយសដ៏សមស្រប, ផ្ដល់នូវតំណភ្ជាប់ទៅកាន់អាជ្ញាបណ្ណ, និងបញ្ជាក់ប្រាប់បើមានការកែប្រែ។ អ្នកអាចធ្វើដូច្នោះបានទៅតាមលក្ខខណ្ឌសមស្របណាមួយ តែមិនតាមលក្ខណ្ឌណាមួយដែល​ណែនាំអ្នកផ្តល់​អាជ្ញាបណ្ណ​ឲ្យយល់ព្រមបញ្ជាក់ឲ្យអ្នក ឬការប្រើរបស់អ្នកឡើយ;<br/><b>ShareAlike</b> - បើអ្នកកាត់តចងក្រង, ផ្លាស់ប្ដូរទ្រង់ទ្រាយ, ឬបន្ថែមខ្លឹមសារលើឯកសារនេះ អ្នកត្រូវតែចែកចាយ ការរួមចំណែករបស់អ្នកក្រោម​អាជ្ញាបណ្ណប្រភពដើមតែមួយ;<br/><b>មិនមានការកម្រិតលក្ខខណ្ឌបន្ថែម</b> - អ្នកមិនអាចដាក់លក្ខខណ្ឌបន្ថែម ឬដាក់វិធានការបច្ចេកវិទ្យាដែលកម្រិតលក្ខខណ្ឌតាមផ្លូវច្បាប់ដល់អ្នកផ្សេងទៀតមិនឲ្យធ្វើអ្វីមួយដែលអាជ្ញាបណ្ណនេះអនុញ្ញាតឡើយ។
</p>
<h2>កំណត់សម្គាល់:</h2>
<p>អ្នកមិនចាំបាច់អនុវត្តតាមអាជ្ញាបណ្ណនេះចំពោះផ្នែកនានានៃឯកសារជាសាធារណៈនេះ ឬផ្នែកនៃការប្រើប្រាស់របស់អ្នកត្រូវបានអនុញ្ញាតតាមរយៈការលើកលែង ឬការកំណត់ដែលអាចប្រើប្រាស់; មិនមានការធានាណាមួយដែលត្រូវបានផ្ដល់ឲ្យនោះឡើយ។ អាជ្ញាបណ្ណមិនអាចផ្ដល់ឲ្យអ្នកនូវរាល់ការអនុញ្ញាតប្រើប្រាស់សម្រាប់គោលបំណង់ចាំបាច់ទាំងអស់បានទេ។ ឧទាហរណ៍ៈ សិទ្ធិផ្សេងៗ​ដូចជា ការផ្សាយជាសាធារណៈ, ឯកជនភាព, ឬសិទ្ធិក្រោមសីលធម៌អាច​កម្រិតរបៀបដែលអ្នកប្រើប្រាស់នេះ​។</p>]]></string>
    <!-- This is the translation guidelines that users must agree to before using the app. It is formatted as HTML. Translation on this will wait until we can find a reliable source -->
    <string name="translation_guidlines"><![CDATA[<h1>គោលការណែនាំអំពីការបកប្រែ</h1>
<p><em>The following statement on the principles and procedures used in translation is subscribed to by all member organizations of and contributors to the <xliff:g id="organization_name">Wycliffe Associates</xliff:g> project. All translation activities are carried out according to these common guidelines.</em></p>
<p>
  <strong>ត្រឹមត្រូវ</strong> - ត្រូវបកប្រែឲ្យបានត្រឹមត្រូវ​ ដោយមិន detracting from ប្តូរ ឬ adding to អត្ថន័យអត្ថបទច្បាប់ដើម. ខ្លឹមសារដែលបានបកប្រែគួរព្យាយាមរក្សាអត្ថន័យនៃអត្ថបទច្បាប់ដើមឲ្យបានល្អតាមដែលអាចធ្វើទៅបានឲ្យដូចដែលត្រូវបានយល់ដោយអ្នកអានច្បាប់ដើម។
  <br/><br/><strong>ច្បាស់</strong> - ត្រូវប្រើរចនាសម្ព័នភាសាណាក៏បានដែលចាំបាច់ដើម្បីទទួលបានការយល់ដឹងកម្រិតខ្ពស់បំផុត។ This includes rearranging the form of a text and using as many or as few terms as necessary to communicate the original meaning as accurately as possible.
  <br/><br/><strong>ទៀងត្រង់</strong> - ត្រូវប្រើពាក្យគន្លឹះដែលមានអត្ថន័យស្មើគ្នានឹងវាក្យសព្ទនៃភាសាច្បាប់ដើមព្រះគន្ពីរ. Terms addressing the relationship between God the Father and God the Son should be retained in translated content and clarified, as needed, in footnotes or other supplemental resources.
  <br/><br/><strong>Authoritative</strong> - Use the original language biblical texts as the highest authority for translation of biblical content. Reliable biblical content in other languages may be used for clarification and as intermediary source texts.
  <br/><br/><strong>Pure</strong> - Avoid any political, denominational, ideological, social, cultural, or theological bias in your translation.
  <br/><br/><strong>Expressive</strong> - Communicate the feelings and attitudes of the original text. As much as possible, maintain the literary forms in the original text, including narrative, poetry, exhortation, and prophecy, representing them with corresponding forms that communicate in a similar way in your language.
  <br/><br/><strong>Historical</strong> - Communicate historical events and facts accurately, providing additional information as needed in order to accurately communicate the intended message to people who do not share the same context and culture as the original recipients of the original content.
  <br/><br/><strong>Natural</strong> - Use language forms that are effective and that reflect the way your language is used in corresponding contexts.
  <br/><br/><strong>Collaborative</strong> - Where possible, work together with other believers who speak your language to translate, check, and distribute the translated content, ensuring that it is of the highest quality and available to as many people as possible.
  <br/><br/><strong>Ongoing</strong> - Encourage the periodic review of translations to ascertain when revision or a new translation is needed.
</p>
<h1>Managing and Identifying Translation Quality</h1>
<p>The quality of a translation generally refers to the fidelity of the translation to the meaning of the original, and the degree to which the translation is understandable and effective for the speakers of the receptor language. The strategy we suggest involves checking the forms and communicative quality of the translation with the language community, and checking the fidelity of the translation with the Church in that people group.</p>
<p>The specific steps involved may vary significantly, depending on the language and context of the translation project. Generally, we consider a good translation to be one that is:</p>
<p>
  <strong>Accurate</strong> - Faithful to the intended meaning of the original, as determined by the Church in that people group and in alignment with the Church global and historical, and consequently:
  <br/><br/><strong>Affirmed by the Church</strong> - Endorsed and used by the Church.
</p>
<p>In addition, a good translation is reviewed by the speakers of the language community and is found to be:</p>
<p>
  <strong>Natural</strong> - Using current forms of the language, and
  <br/><br/><strong>Clear</strong> - Strives for the highest level of comprehension by hearers.
</p>]]></string>
    <!-- This is the statement of faith that users must agree to before using the app. It is formatted as HTML. Translation on this will wait until we have a reliable source -->
    <string name="statement_of_faith"><![CDATA[<h1>សេចក្តីថ្លែងការណ៍នៃជំនឿ</h1>
<p>
  ព្រះគម្ពីរទាំងមូលត្រូវបានបំផុសគំនិតដោយព្រះ ហើយមានអំណាច។
  <br/><br/>​គោលលទ្ធិនៃមានព្រះតែមួយ ហើយទ្រង់ជាបុគ្គលបីនាក់ គឺព្រះបិតា ព្រះរាជបុត្រ និងព្រះវិញ្ញាណដ៏វិសុទ្ធ។ 
 <br/><br/>ដោយសារតែការធ្លាក់ចុះនៃមនុស្សជាតិ មនុស្សទាំងអស់មានចំណង់ធ្វើអំពើបាប ហើយមានតម្រូវការសម្រាប់សេចក្តីសង្គ្រោះ
  <br/><br/>​ការសុគតរបស់ព្រះគ្រិស្តជាសេចក្តីជំនួសសម្រាប់អ្នកមានបាប​ ។
  <br/><br/>គោលលទ្ធិនៃ​មនុស្សបានសុចរិតដោយសេចក្តីជំនឿ​។
  <br/><br/>​មនុស្សទាំងអស់នឹងរស់ឡើងវិញ ទាំងករណីសុចរិត ទាំងករណីនុច្ចរិត។   
<br/><br/>​អ្នកដែលបានទទួលសេចក្តីសង្គ្រោះនឹងទទួលជីវិតអស់កល្បជានិច្ច ហើយអ្នកដែលមិនទទួលសេចក្តីសង្គ្រោះនឹងទទួលការដាក់ទណ្ឌកម្មអស់កល្បជានិច្ច។ </p>]]></string>
</resources>
